<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marcos Barbero's Blog</title>
    <description>I create things and I blog about it... sometimes.</description>
    <link>http://0.0.0.0:4000</link>
    <atom:link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Integrating Vault with Spring Cloud Config Server</title>
        <description>
          
          This guide walks through the process of creating a central configuration management for microservices using Spring Cloud Config integrating with HashiCorp Vault. Introduction Nowadays, software is commonly delivered as a service and doesn’t matter the programming language that was chosen, it’s always good to follow the twelve-factor app methodology. The...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/integrating-vault-spring-cloud-config/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/integrating-vault-spring-cloud-config/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>User impersonation with Spring Security</title>
        <description>
          
          This guide walks through the process of creating an user impersonation from super / admin users with spring security. Overview It’s a common use-case for secured applications that the admin / super users to be able to login as any other user. It can be helpful for use cases such...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/user-impersonation-with-spring-security/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/user-impersonation-with-spring-security/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adding Rate Limit for Spring Cloud Netflix Zuul</title>
        <description>
          
          In the development of APIs sometimes it’s necessary to control the rate of the traffic received by the network to prevent attacks such as DoS or to limit the number of requests a single user/origin can make to a certain endpoint. In a microservices architecture the API Gateway is the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/spring-cloud-netflix-zuul-rate-limit/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/spring-cloud-netflix-zuul-rate-limit/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HA and Zone Affinity With Spring Cloud Netflix Eureka</title>
        <description>
          
          This tutorial will guide you through the process to setup zone affinity in Spring Cloud Netflix Eureka. What You Will Build You will build three applications: API Gateway - Spring Cloud Netflix Zuul Service Registry - Spring Cloud Netflix Eureka REST Service - Spring Cloud All those are necessary to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/ha-and-zone-affinity-spring-cloud-eureka/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/ha-and-zone-affinity-spring-cloud-eureka/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Setup multiple DataSources with Spring Boot and Spring Data in PCF</title>
        <description>
          
          This tutorial will guide you in the process to setup Spring Data to access multiple SQL services in PCF. What you will build You will build an application that connects to multiple MySQL services in PCF. Pre-req JDK 1.8 Text editor or your favorite IDE Maven 3.0+ PCF For this...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/setup-multiple-datasources-with-spring-boot-spring-data-in-pcf/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/setup-multiple-datasources-with-spring-boot-spring-data-in-pcf/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Multiple MongoDB connectors with Spring Boot</title>
        <description>
          
          This tutorial will guide you in the process to connect to multiple MongoDBs. What you will build You will build an application that connects to multiple MongoDBs. Pre-req JDK 1.8 Text editor or your favorite IDE Maven 3.0+ MongoDB The sample project uses Project Lombok to generate getters, setters, contructors,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/multiple-mongodb-connectors-in-spring-boot/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/multiple-mongodb-connectors-in-spring-boot/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Creating a batch service</title>
        <description>
          
          This tutorial will guide you in the process to create a batch processing solution. What you will build You will build a service that imports a CSV spreadsheet, transform it in a Java object and stores in a SQL database. Pre-req JDK 1.8 Text editor or your favorite IDE Maven...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/creating-a-batch-service/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://0.0.0.0:4000/creating-a-batch-service/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
