<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marcos Barbero's Blog</title>
    <description>Eu crio coisas e escrevo sobre isso... às vezes.</description>
    <link>http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR</link>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Graceful Shutdown Spring Boot Applications</title>
        <description>
          
          This guide walks through the process of graceful shutdown a Spring Boot application. The implementation of this blog post is originally created by Andy Wilkinson and it was based on this GitHub comment. Introduction A lot of developers and architects discuss about the application design, traffic load, frameworks, patterns to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/graceful-shutdown-spring-boot-apps/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/graceful-shutdown-spring-boot-apps/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Optional Dependency Injection using Spring</title>
        <description>
          
          This guide walks through the options available to inject optional dependencies with Spring DI. Introduction There are quite a few use-cases where it’s needed to make optional some of the dependencies injected, here are some of them: Provide a default implementation whenever a required infrastructure dependency is not provided, such...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/optional-di-spring/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/optional-di-spring/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Integrating Vault with Spring Cloud Config Server</title>
        <description>
          
          This guide walks through the process of creating a central configuration management for microservices using Spring Cloud Config integrating with HashiCorp Vault. Introduction Nowadays, software is commonly delivered as a service and doesn’t matter the programming language that was chosen, it’s always good to follow the twelve-factor app methodology. The...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/integrating-vault-spring-cloud-config/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/integrating-vault-spring-cloud-config/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>User impersonation with Spring Security</title>
        <description>
          
          This guide walks through the process of creating an user impersonation from super / admin users with spring security. Overview It’s a common use-case for secured applications that the admin / super users to be able to login as any other user. It can be helpful for use cases such...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/user-impersonation-with-spring-security/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/user-impersonation-with-spring-security/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Adding Rate Limit for Spring Cloud Netflix Zuul</title>
        <description>
          
          In the development of APIs sometimes it’s necessary to control the rate of the traffic received by the network to prevent attacks such as DoS or to limit the number of requests a single user/origin can make to a certain endpoint. In a microservices architecture the API Gateway is the...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/spring-cloud-netflix-zuul-rate-limit/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/spring-cloud-netflix-zuul-rate-limit/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HA and Zone Affinity With Spring Cloud Netflix Eureka</title>
        <description>
          
          This tutorial will guide you through the process to setup zone affinity in Spring Cloud Netflix Eureka. What You Will Build You will build three applications: API Gateway - Spring Cloud Netflix Zuul Service Registry - Spring Cloud Netflix Eureka REST Service - Spring Cloud All those are necessary to...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/ha-and-zone-affinity-spring-cloud-eureka/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/ha-and-zone-affinity-spring-cloud-eureka/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Configurando mutiplos DataSources com Spring Boot e Spring Data - PCF</title>
        <description>
          
          Esse tutorial te guiará no processo de configurar Spring Data para acessar múltiplos serviços SQL na PCF. O que você irá construir Você construirá uma aplicação que conecta com vários serviços MySQL na PCF. Pre-req JDK 1.8 Editor de texto ou sua IDE favorita Maven 3.0+ PCF Nesse tutorial eu...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/setup-multiple-datasources-with-spring-boot-spring-data-in-pcf/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/setup-multiple-datasources-with-spring-boot-spring-data-in-pcf/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Conectando multiplos MongoDBs usando Spring Boot</title>
        <description>
          
          Esse tutorial te guiará no processo de conectar uma aplicação com multiplos MongoDBs. O que você construirá Você construirá uma aplicação que se conecta à multiplos MongoDBs. Pre-req JDK 1.8 Editor de texto ou sua IDE favorita Maven 3.0+ MongoDB O projeto de examplo usa Project Lombok para gerar getters,...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/multiple-mongodb-connectors-in-spring-boot/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/multiple-mongodb-connectors-in-spring-boot/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Criando um serviço batch</title>
        <description>
          
          Esse tutorial te guiará no processo de criação de uma solução de processamento batch. O que você irá criar Você irá construir um serviço que importa os dados de uma planilha CSV, transforma em um objeto java e armazena em um banco de dados SQL. Pré-requisitos JDK 1.8 Editor de...
        </description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/creating-a-batch-service/
        </link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">
          http://blog.marcosbarbero.com/pt_BR/creating-a-batch-service/
        </guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
